landlordzone.co.uk 2018-01-30

# Privacy - LandlordZONE

**Privacy Policy and Cookies** – Parkmatic Publications Limited trading as LandlordZONE® is committed to providing you with the highest quality service.

This includes maintaining your privacy and protecting your personal data. In addition to our **Website Terms of Use** the following policy explains what we and our associated publications do with the personal data we collect about you.

To get the best from our services, please keep your personal data (including your email address) accurate and up to date. You can do this by up-dating any account information you currently have with us. Always keep any user names and passwords safe and secure.

Generally we do not collect particularly sensitive information beyond name, e-mail, and usually optionally postal address and telephone number, unless you are using the TenatVERIFY or LandlordDEALS account services.

Please take the time to read this privacy policy carefully.

By registering and opening an on-line account with us you consent to our use of your personal data in accordance with our terms of use policy. We hope that by implementing and operating this policy we will make your on-line experience a secure and enjoyable one.

We will never share you personal data with third parties; that is an absolute promise.

### Contents:

  * What personal data do we collect about you?
  * How do we use your personal data?
  * Safeguarding your personal data?
  * What are cookies and how do we use them?
  * Sale of the business
  * Contacting us

### 1: Why do we have a privacy policy?

There are a number of UK, and international laws which set out important standards regarding information that identifies a living individual. This is known as “personal data.”

All UK organisations processing personal data must do so fairly and lawfully. They must also be registered with the UK Information Commissioner whose role it is to ensure that organisations comply with their data processing obligations. If you want to, you can view a copy of our data protection notification by visiting the Information Commissioner’s website.

Our UK Data Protection Registration Number is: Z2161622. Certain rules apply to sending direct marketing information by telephone and email. At Parkmatic Publications Limited we treat all of our obligations seriously and take all necessary steps to comply when we store and process your personal data.

### 2: What personal data do we collect about you and how?

It is essential that we collect, store and process some of your personal data so that we can give you the best service experience and perform our services efficiently. Some of the information we request is voluntary, and you do not have to provide it.

### We collect your personal data in a number of different ways, including the following:

  * if you provide it when communicating with us (for example when registering for our services);
  * if you order any of our products or services;
  * if you enter a competition or promotion;
  * if you make payments or modify your account details; and
  * when you visit our websites (for example by cookies and other browser-generated information).

### 3: How do we use your personal data?

We retain and use your personal data for the following main purposes:

  * we reserve the right to access and disclose your personal data if we are required to do so by law.
  * providing our services, contacting you and servicing our relationship with you; administration and accounting, billing and auditing and other legal purposes;
  * security, payment verification, preventing and detecting money laundering, fraud and other crime, insurance, credit assessment and administration, tracing debtors and recovering debt. For these purposes, we may also pass on your personal data to third parties;
  * generating statistics on our users, such as the popularity of certain of our services, about the “traffic” visiting our websites. When we do this, your data becomes anonymous and you are not personally identified; and
  * we never sell or share your contact details (e-mail addresses etc) with third parties but we may e-mail broadcast to you from our own servers on advertisers’ behalf where we feel they offer services which may be of use to landlords and property investors.

### 4: Safeguarding your personal data

We take all reasonable care in the collection, storage, processing and disclosure of your personal data and have implemented internal security procedures so as to minimise the risk that unauthorised parties will be able to access the information.

Nonetheless, the Internet is an open medium and we cannot guarantee that any information you send to us by email or via our website will not be intercepted or tampered with. To help protect any sensitive personal data and minimise the risk of it being intercepted by unauthorised third parties our secure servers employ industry standard Secure Socket Layer v3 (SSL) or Transport Layer  
Security v1 (TLS) encryption when you submit information to us through our website, for example when using TenantVERIFY. This security is signified by the “https” and the padlock on the URL bar.

Some older browsers do not allow the use of current SSL technology and we therefore recommend that you use an up-to-date browser for example we recommend Google Chrome. If you use Microsoft Internet Explorer use version 9.0 or later.

You can also help to protect your personal data, by following these guidelines:

  * choose a password that you will be able to remember but that would be hard for someone to guess. Ideally it should include special characters (such as “?” or “#” for example) and numbers. We recommend that you change it regularly and if you need to write it down, always keep it in a safe place; better still use a password manager on your computer which encrypts the information.
  * make sure that no-one can see the details you are entering when you log-in;
  * if other people have access to your computer, remember to close your browser each time you log-off and end your session and, if possible, clear any history of the websites you have visited and that your browser may have saved or “cached”; and never disclose your access details to anyone.

### 5: Our data and information enquiry handling process will ensure that:

  * a systematic approach is taken to receiving and dealing with all enquiries which are fully documented and acknowledged.
  * all required and appropriate steps will be taken to fully investigate any claims
  * enquiries will be handled efficiently and promptly
  * all information is retained in the event that a re-evaluation of the case is required
  * legislative timescales are always met
  * applicants can see the transparent process by which their enquiry is being/has been handled
  * all staff can deal immediately with a request in the appropriate manner and will understand the circumstances in which guidance must be sought from senior management.

### 6: What are cookies and how do we use them?

Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and allows us to improve our site. For more detailed information on the cookies and the purpose for which we use them see the information about cookies below.

### 7: Sale of the business

In the event that the Parkmatic Publications Limited business is sold fully or in part, integrated with another business, or it disposes of its rights and obligations under any agreement with you, your records may be disclosed under appropriate confidentiality terms to our advisers and any prospective purchasers’ advisers, and will be passed onto the new owners with strict conditions attached, which include maintaining our privacy policy.

### 7: Contacting Us

You can contact us using the Contact link on our websites. You may also contact us by telephone list on our Contact page.

Please bear in mind that this privacy policy only applies to websites and services operated by Parkmatic Publications Limited and not those operated by third parties, including those to which our websites may link. We suggest that you check out the privacy policies operated by third party websites before providing personal information about yourself.

### Information about Cookies

Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve our site.

A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we store on your browser or the hard drive of your device if you agree to this. Cookies collect information that is transferred to your computer’s hard drive.

At Parkmatic Publications Limited our priority is to provide a smooth experience for you while using our website, therefore rather than regularly asking for your consent as you move around our website, we have removed the majority of non-essential cookies from our website.

### Types of Cookies in Use

You can find information about types of cookies in the table below:

**Essential Cookies** – Essential cookies are used by website providers in order to make the website work and can also be used to remember essential information, such as information about which web pages you use, downloads etc. Parkmatic Publications Limited uses essential cookies where necessary.

**Session Cookies** – Session cookies are temporary cookies that only exist for the period you access the website until you close the browser after accessing the website. Session cookies are automatically deleted from your device when you close your browser. Session cookies can help Parkmatic Publications Limited to remember your movements from page to page, therefore avoiding having to re-enter information. The Session Cookies used by Parkmatic Publications Limited do not record or store any personal information about you.

**Persistent Cookies** – Persistent cookies remain on your device after you have visited the website and are not deleted when the browser is closed. Persistent cookies can retain your preferences and allow those preferences to be used in future visits to the site. Parkmatic may use a persistent cookie to remember if you requested that our website remembers your login details.

**Tracking Cookies** – Tracking cookies can be used to analyse your usage of a website or e-mal broadcasts. These cookies may not identify you personally and are simply used to understand how clients use the website and to make improvements to the website. Some tracking cookies are placed by third party advertisers. These cookies are commonly used to evaluate the effectiveness of a company’s advertising.

### Restricting Cookies

If you wish to restrict or block the cookies set by us, or indeed any other website, you can do this with your browser settings.

The Help function within your browser should tell you how to do this. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our website or you may not be able to use the website as expected.

To view any cookies that have been placed on your computer following visits to ours or other websites you can check your browser history.

If you still have any queries or concerns you can contact us here

See our Website Terms and Conditions of Use

See our Advertising Terms and Conditions of Use
